POOJA JAIN

SUMMARY

Critical thinker and graduate student at Berkeley School of Information with three years of experience in delivering strategic solutions across domains like ERP systems, Web Analytics and Business Intelligence. Extensive background in Client Relationships and Analytics.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley

Expected: May, 2017

New Delhi, 2008-2012

Interest areas: Product Management, Business Intelligence, Analytics

MS in Information Management and Systems [GPA: 3.67]

Bachelors of Technology (Information Technology) [GPA: 3.75]

Awarded Student of the year award 2012.

EXPERIENCE

GRADUATE STUDENT INSTRUCTOR

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Aug 2015 - Present

UC Berkeley, California [Courses: Statistical models and Probability]

Currently tutoring and mentoring cohort of 30 students on Statistics and responsible for their management & administration.

SAP BI CONSULTANT Nov 2014 – July 2013

Century I.T Solutions, India [Environment: SAP BI 7.0, ECC6]

- Led the team of 5 responsible for Data Extraction and Loading (ETL) operations for Fortune 500 client ConAgra Foods.
- Handled Business Intelligence operations with the senior consultants to implement process chains for Master data and Transaction data loads to automate the process and increased the efficiency by more than 50%.
- Worked with SAP R/3 Logistics (LO) in loading Sales and Distribution data from ECC into BI systems and creation of Batch process and scheduling load jobs in parallel.
- Collaborated with business stakeholders of Glaspac client and led the documentation team in developing Business Requirement Documents and Software Requirement Specifications.

BUSINESS TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

Oct 2012 - July 2014

Aricent Technologies, India

- Managed a team of 4 while working on Analytics testing project; made analytical test cases to incorporate the user requirements based on websites and mobile applications like those of CNN, NBA and TruTV.
- Led the quality assurance team to ensure low defect rate in codebase in C language; collaborated with clients to create test environments that reproduce their setups, ensured high software quality through functional, end-to-end and performance testing.
- Integrated analytical API's like Adobe Omniture and Site catalyst in the online application of *NBA* client for applying real-time analytics and detailed segmentation to power customer intelligence for business.
- Designed, developed and tested enterprise level products for Nokia Siemens Network which aided in improving the code & bug fixing.
- Received appraisal for improving the speed of the web application of CNN client by almost 70% by configuring filters of Google's PageSpeed module in Apache server.

TECHNOLOGY INTERN, Indian Oil Corporation Limited

Summer 2011

 Developed a web-based portal 'Consumable Management System' on .NET platform to provide inventory management features for Indian Oil employees to issue consumables, place order to vendors and conduct audits on available stock.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

${\tt UC\,Berkeley\,CalCentral\,Financial\,Planning\,System}$

Fall-2015

Conceptualized and created an application to empower UC Berkeley students to better understand their finances and plan for the future. Carried out contextual inquiries, developed personas, prototypes and wireframes.

Hand Gesture Recognition System

Spring-2012

Implemented convexity detection method to detect & recognize real-time hand gestures using C# and WPF in .NET

Bluetooth Based Multimedia Application

Fall-2011

Developed a system application 'Media Player' in JAVA which could be controlled from the system as well as from a Bluetooth enabled mobile

KEY SKILLSETS

Languages: C++, Python, SQL, UNIX Scripting, HTML, JSP

Database: Oracle 10g SQL

Tools & Software Frameworks: SAP BI 7.0, SAP Business Objects, SAP ECC 6.0, gdb, UltraEdit, Eclipse, Github, JIRA, NewRelic

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded with Meritorious Student Award in school for six consecutive years from 2003 to 2008.
- Got "Client Focus Delivery" core value award in Century IT Solutions for the outstanding work done for the clients.
- Received "You Make a Difference" award for team development excellence in Aricent Technologies.